

Serghei lakovlev

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · TECHNICAL MANAGER

Kviv Ukraine

📱 +380 (68) 611-73-20 | 🗷 egrep@protonmail.ch | $wilde{ wildet{\textit{w}}}$ May 16th, 1983 | 💣 serghei.blog | 🖸 sergeyklay | 🛅 egrep

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

I'm a software engineer with 20 years of experience in IT who enjoys finding elegant solutions to non-trivial problems. I'm focused on the goal and driven by visual sophistication and laser-sharp precision, I take pride in every finished project, and never stop learning along the way. I work as the head of development with 20 teams of 90+ engineers to develop airSlate - better nocode workflow automation platform.

Education

Russian New University (RosNOU)

Moscow, Russia

Mar. 2017 - May. 2017

B.S. IN APPLIED INFORMATICS IN ECONOMICS Sep. 2004 - Jun. 2008

Cources & Certifications

Jetbrains Jetbrains Academy

Python Core Sep. 2021 - PRESENT

Jetbrains Jetbrains Academy

Kotlin Developer Sep. 2020 - Oct. 2020

Computer Science Center Stepic

HASKELL Dec. 2018 - Feb. 2019

 Yandex
 Coursera

 C++ Yellow Belt
 May. 2017 - Jun. 2017

Yandex Coursera

Skills & Endorsements

C++ WHITE BELT

Team Work Leadership, Problem Solving, Team Management, Expectations Management

DevOps AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Vagrant, Packer, Jenkins, TeamCity, GitHub Actions

Back-end Django, Flask, Symfony, Laravel, Phalcon, Elasticsearch, REST API

Front-end HTML5, CSS, SASS

APM Newrelic, Grafana, Kibana, Jaeger

Databases MySQL, SQLite, Redis

Programming Python, PHP, C/C++, Go, Kotlin, Haskell, SQL, XML, Elisp, <u>MEX</u>

Languages Russian, English, Ukrainian **Operating Systems** Linux, macOS, Windows

Development Tools CMake, Intellij IDEA, Emacs, Vim, Make, gcc, gdb, git, zsh, bash

Employment History

airSlate, Inc. Kyiv, Ukraine

DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT Dec. 2021 - Present

- · Growing the engineering teams and teams productivity.
- · Building a development course.
- Building a world-class engineering teams.
- Accelerating teams speed.
- Working on SDLC area.
- · Improving product Quality Assurance.
- Product performance & speed.
- · Ensuring safety.

airSlate, Inc. Kyiv, Ukraine

Aug. 2021 - Dec. 2021 R&D TEAM LEAD, TECH MANAGER

- Researching the impact of services design on user experience and product performance.
- Development load tests using Scala, Gatling, InfluxDB, Prometheus and Grafana.
- Delegating tasks and conducting performance reviews.
- Coordinating with other managers.
- Development of experimental CI/CD tools, research in the field of new technologies.
- Public API design.
- R&D Team leadership.
- · Internal reports and meetups.

airSlate, Inc. Kyiv, Ukraine

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2021 SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

- Design of new features and internal products on field of workflow automation.
- New features review and approvals.
- Product performance improvements, new features review and approvals.
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, GitHub Actions, and several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- I have been management many tech leads.
- Internal reports and meetups.

Zephir Washington, United States

CO-OWNER Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2020

- Core Team Member, Contributor, Maintainer, Co-Owner, Core Developer.
- · My contributions included performance optimization and compilation speed, chasing bugs both in the compiler and kernel, unit testing, implementing new features in the language, maintaining projects, code review, releasing and more.

Phalcon Washington, United States

BOARD MEMBER Jan. 2015 - Aug. 2020

- Core Team Member, Contributor, Maintainer, Co-Author, Core Developer.
- · My contributions included performance optimization, security and stability fixes, unit tests, packaging for Ubuntu and Windows, CI/CD, translations, maintaining projects and more.

PDFfiller, Inc. Kyiv, Ukraine

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Now. 2015 - Jan. 2020

- · Support PDFfiller.com and create new features and internal products.
- Implemented backend services and tools using C++, C, PHP, MySQL, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ.
- · Product Dockerization, build service discovery using Consul, working with AWS stack, CI/CD design and implementation.
- · Code review and interviews of new employees.
- · Design and implementation monitoring and alerting tools based on ELK stack, InfluxDB, Slack and Grafana.
- Implemented internal Distributed File System (WebDAV like).
- Implemented a mass mailing service with analytics and statistics (Mailgun like).
- Implemented internal Chaos Engineering service to test the company's products and services.
- · Internal reports and meetups.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Genesis Kyiv, Ukraine

Sep. 2014 - Nov. 2015

• Implemented a mass mailing service with analytics and statistics (Mailgun like).

- Implemented backend services and tools using PHP, C, XLST, MySQL (Percona).

· Internal reports and meetups.

NetGame Kyiv, Ukraine

Sep. 2013 - Aug. 2014 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Development and support of gambling services.
- Implemented backend services and tools using Linux, Nginx, PHP, Yii Framework, PostgreSQL, JavaScript and Bazaar.

Self-Employment WWW

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2009 - Aug. 2014

- I have done freelance work and been self-employed for 5 years here.
- · Implemented projects for the National Association of Power Engineers of Russia, various businesses, E-Shops and freight carriers.
- Moderation Drupal Framework forum community and help newbies.
- Used stack: Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP and JavaScript.

Art. Lebedev Studio

Moscow, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2008 - Dec. 2008

- Development new features for existing clients of the company.
- · Used stack: Windows, PHP, XML, XLST, MySQL.

Blog.ru Moscow, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2007 - May 2008

- Development new features for the blogging service and social networks.
- · Used stack: Linux, Apache, PHP, JS, MySQL.

Gamma Group Moscow, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2006 - Oct. 2007

- Support corporate websites and development new features.
- Used stack: Linux, Apache, PHP, JS, MySQL.

Arsilor Moscow, Russia

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER Feb. 2005 - May 2006

- E-shop development, maintenance of the company's websites.
- Used stack: Linux, Apache, PHP, Joomla/Mambo CMS, PHP Nuke, JS, MySQL.

Tsar's courtyard Moscow, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2004 - Dec 2004

- · Implemented solutions for automating accounting and management accounting.
- Used stack: Windows, Delphi, FoxPro, MySQL.

Extracurricular Activity

django-environ

Maintainer 2021 - PRESENT

- Languages: Python
- **Description:** A Python package that allows you to use Twelve-factor methodology to configure your Django application with environment variables.
- URL: https://github.com/joke2k/django-environ

python-airslate

Creator, Maintainer 2021 - PRESENT

- Languages: Python
- Description: A Python client library has been designed to quickly and easily implement the airSlate REST API.
- URL: https://github.com/airslate-oss/python-airslate

gstore

CREATOR, MAINTAINER 2020 - PRESENT

- Languages: Python
- Description: A simple tool to synchronize GitHub repositories of your organizations.
- URL: https://github.com/sergeyklay/gstore

esup

Maintainer 2020 - PRESENT

- · Languages: ELisp
- Description: A GNU Emacs Start Up Profiler.
- URL: https://github.com/jschaf/esup

bnf-mode

CREATOR, MAINTAINER 2019 - PRESENT

- Languages: ELisp
- Description: A GNU Emacs major mode for editing BNF grammars.
- URL: https://github.com/sergeyklay/bnf-mode

jaeger-client-php

Maintainer 2018 - PRESENT

- Languages: Apache Thrift, PHP
- Description: A client-side library that can be used to instrument PHP apps for distributed trace collection, and to send those traces to Jaeger.
- URL: https://github.com/jonahgeorge/jaeger-client-php

Qless PHP

CREATOR, MAINTAINER 2018 - PRESENT

- Languages: Lua, PHP
- Description: PHP Bindings for Qless.
- URL: https://github.com/pdffiller/qless-php

idea-plugin

Maintainer 2015 - 2020

- Languages: Java, Kotlin
- Description: IntelliJ plugin for editing Zephir code. Provides syntax definition, autocompletion and syntax check support.
- URL: https://github.com/zephir-lang/idea-plugin

Codeception

TEAM MEMBER, MAINTAINER 2015 - PRESENT

- Languages: PHP
- **Description:** A full-stack testing PHP framework.
- URL: https://github.com/Codeception/Codeception

Zephir

Maintainer 2016 - 2020

- Languages: C, Zephir, PHP, Zend Engine
- Description: A high level programming language that eases the creation and maintainability of extensions for PHP.
- URL: https://github.com/zephir-lang/zephir

cphalcon

 CORE TEAM MEMBER
 2015 - 2020

- Languages: C, Zephir, PHP, Zend Engine
- **Description:** An open source web framework delivered as a C extension for the PHP language providing high performance and lower resource consumption.
- URL: https://github.com/phalcon/cphalcon

Publications

Phalcon Cookbook.

https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MXDECCR

Co-author 2016

· Phalcon Framework Cookbook.